Daniel Calvo

(510) 846-4484 · dcalvo@leomail.tamuc.edu

<u>Summary</u>

A technical professional pursuing a career in the web development industry. Strong collaborative experience from a supply chain setting and excels in educational environments. Passionate for learning and sharpening technical skills to enhance business efficiency.

Experience

Hayward Unified School District

Hayward, CA

District Webmaster

January 2022 – Present

- Evaluate web pages using WCAG 2.0 guidelines to recommend critical fixes to site administrators.
- Create training documentation to encourage best practices for a non-technical audience.
- Promote accessibility awareness by educating site administrators to prioritize users with disabilities.
- Manage and publish over 30 different school and district websites for public access.

Alameda County Community Food Bank

Data Analyst

July 2020 – October 2021

- Enhance Excel reports with VBA scripts to extract and visualize distribution metrics.
- Design custom VBA scripts and process improvements to reduce overall data entry workload.
- Optimize Jet Reports with pivot tables and other assessment functions to process data for over 5 million pounds of food each month.

Texas A&M University-Commerce

Commerce, TX

Digital Accessibility Specialist

January 2017 – December 2019

- Improved content quality of the university website by 30% with Cascade CMS and Siteimprove.
- Standardized the university website accessibility with WCAG 2.0 to meet AA level compliance.
- Collaborated with the EIR Accessibility Officer to provide live technical support and software training for university faculty and staff.

Leadership Experience

Texas A&M University-Commerce

Commerce, TX

Resident Assistant

July 2020 – Present

- Reinforced residential policies to maintain a safe, inclusive, and educational environment.
- Conducted hall programs to spread university resources and offer engaging learning activities.
- Provided year-round academic and emotional support for student residents.

Education

Texas A&M University-Commerce, Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, 2019

GPA: Major: 3.7/4.0, Cumulative: 3.5/4.0

<u>Additional</u>

- Languages: Fluent in English and Tagalog; Conversational in Ilocano
- Technology: HTML, CSS, Javascript, and VBA; SiteImprove, Cascade CMS, Jet Reports, Dynamics NAV
- Interests: Finance, Travel, and Fitness